Ah, there it is. My house.
啊，就在那儿，我的老家
And good old Cleveland Street. How could I ever forget it?
还有亲切如昔的克利夫兰大街， 教我如何能从记忆中抹去呢？
And there I am, with that dumb round face and...
那边那个就是我，傻乎乎的圆脸蛋
that stupid stocking cap.
戴着顶蠢透了的绒线帽
But no matter. Christmas was on its way.
可有什么关系呢，圣诞就要来临了
Lovely, glorious, beautiful Christmas...
可爱的，欢乐的，美丽的圣诞啊
around which the entire kid year revolved.
一个孩子的一整年都是围着它转的
Downtown Hohman was prepared for its yearly bacchanalia of...
市中心霍曼大道上人们正为准备一年一度的
peace on earth and good will to men.
以“和平临世界，善愿及众生”为主题的酒神节而忙碌
Higbees' corner window was traditionally a high-water mark...
黑比百货店的街角橱窗向来是
of the pre-Christmas season.
圣诞前季的最亮点
First nighters, packed earmuff to earmuff, jostled in wonderment...
赶来看新鲜的人们，万头攒动，叹为观止
before a golden tinkling display...
沉浸在机驱电动，声光幻影的展示
of mechanized, electronic joy.
所带来的欢乐中
Wow, there it is.
哇，它就在那儿
The holy grail of Christmas gifts.
令人梦寐以求的圣诞礼物
The Red Ryder 200-shot range model...
瑞得莱德两百发射击用气枪
And there he is.
那个就是他
Red Ryder himself.
牛仔瑞得莱德
In his hand was the knurled stock of as coolly deadly-looking...
他掌中的原木枪托属于
a piece of weaponry as ever I had laid eyes on.
我生平仅见的最冷血致命的一件武器
For weeks, I had been scheming to get my mitts on one of these...
好几个星期来，我一直在盘算着
fearsome blue-steel beauties.
如何染指那令人生畏的蓝钢尤物
My fevered brain seethed with the effort of trying to come up with...
我滚热的脑袋已经沸腾了
the infinitely subtle devices necessary to implant...
就为了要想出一个天衣无缝的奇谋妙计
the Red Ryder range model air rifle indelibly...
好把瑞得莱德射击用气枪深植入我父母的潜意识
into my parents' subconscious.
让他们永志不忘
Ralphie!
拉尔菲!
Randy!
兰迪!
Down here in two minutes!
两分钟里面就给我下来!
And I mean two minutes!
我说了两分钟!
Come on, Ralphie. I got here first!
好了，拉尔菲，我先来的!
Cut it out.
够了
My mother, grabbing for her copy of Look magazine...
我妈妈拿起这份《看世界》杂志的时候
would find herself cleverly trapped into reading a Red Ryder sales pitch.
会发现她的目光被巧妙地诱导到了 一则瑞得莱德的减价销售广告上了
They traded Bullfrog. I don't believe it.
他们居然要换掉布弗劳格，真不敢相信
What's that?
说什么呢？
Well, for Christ's sake, the Sox traded Bullfrog...
哦，看在上帝的份上，红袜队要用布弗劳格
the only player they've got, for Shottenhoffer.
他们手头上唯一的击球手，来换肖藤霍夫
"Four Eyes" Shottenhoffer, a utility infielder.
“四眼”肖藤霍夫，一个攻守兼备的内野手
Got a whole goddamned team of utility infielders.
他们整个队伍都他妈的是内野手了
That's nice.
那多好啊
Ralphie, on the double!
拉尔菲，给我赶紧!
Did you hear about this guy who swallowed a yo-yo?
你听说了有人吞下了个悠悠吗？
Swallowed a yo-yo?
吞下了个悠悠？
On a bet.
他跟人打赌
Some clodhopper down in Griffith, Indiana.
印地安那州格里菲思那儿的一个乡巴佬
They write the silliest things in the newspapers.
报上尽登这些无聊透顶的玩意儿
What do you mean, silly? I mean that's real news.
你说啥，无聊？ 我说这才是真正的新闻呢
That's not like that politics slop.
这可不象那些倒胃口的政治垃圾
What is the name of the Lone Ranger's nephew's horse?
独行者侄子的马叫什么名字？
Victor. His name is Victor.
维克多，它叫维克多
How the hell did you know that?
见鬼你怎么知道？
Everybody knows that.
谁不知道啊
That's another one of your silly puzzles?
又是你那些无聊的测验题？
Yeah, it's another one of our silly puzzles.
对，又是我那些无聊的测验题
Could be worth $50,000.
但可能会值五万块
What kind is it this time?
这回是什么？
Name the great characters in American literature.
说出美国文学作品里的不朽人物的名字
Victor? The Lone Ranger's nephew's horse?
维克多？独行者侄子的马？
Meanwhile, I struggled for exactly the right BB gun hint.
与此同时，我也在绞尽脑汁在想个好点的关于气枪的暗示
It had to be firm, but subtle.
它必须很有力，但又要不着痕迹
Flick says he saw some grizzly bears near Pulaski's candy store.
佛理克说他在普拉斯基的糖果店周围看到过大灰熊
They looked at me as if I had lobsters crawling out of my ears.
他们瞧着我就仿佛龙虾正从我耳朵眼里钻出来似的
I could tell that I was in imminent danger of over-playing my hand.
我很清楚因为花招玩过火了，我已经快大祸临头了
Casually, I switched tactics.
非常自然的，我改变了策略
Hey, Dad!
嘿，爸爸!
I'll bet you'll never guess what I got you for Christmas.
我打赌你永远猜不着圣诞我要送你什么
A new furnace.
新炉子吗
That's a good one, Dad.
这个猜得不错，爸爸
My old man was one of the most feared furnace-fighters...
我老爸是北印第安纳最令人生畏的火炉斗士之一
Hurry up, you're going to be late for school.
赶快，你们上学要迟到了
Yeah. I'm running late already.
呀，我已经迟了
Round one was over.
第一回合结束了
Parents, one.
大人，一比零
Kids, zip.
孩子，零比一
I could feel the Christmas noose beginning to tighten.
我可以感觉到圣诞的紧箍咒又上紧了一道
Maybe what happened next was inevitable.
也许接着发生的事是不可避免的
Ralphie, what would you like for Christmas?
拉尔菲，你圣诞想要点什么？
Horrified, I heard myself blurt it out.
满怀恐惧地，我听到自己竟然脱口而出
I want an official Red Ryder carbine action 200-shot range model air rifle.
我要一支正牌瑞得莱德半自动200发射击用气枪
No. Shoot your eye out.
不行，会把你眼珠射出来的
Oh, no! It was the classic mother-BB gun block.
哦，不! 经典的妈妈们拒绝气枪进门的挡路牌
"You'll shoot your eye out."
“会把你眼珠射出来的”
That deadly phrase uttered many times before by hundreds...
这句被成千上百个母亲常挂在嘴边的致命杀招
of mothers was not surmountable...
是孩子的世界里任何机变花巧
by any means known to kid-dom.
都无计战胜的
But such was my mania, my desire for a Red Ryder carbine...
但我对瑞得莱德气枪的痴狂和渴望
that I immediately began to rebuild the dike.
足以令我迅速开始重建堤坝
I was just kidding. Even though Flick is getting one.
我开玩笑呢，虽然佛理克就快有一支了
I'd just like some Tinkertoys.
我要几套组合玩具就行了
I couldn't believe my own ears. Tinkertoys?
我都不敢相信我自己的耳朵了，组合玩具？
She'd never buy it.
她说什么也不会买的
BB guns are dangerous.
气枪太危险了
I don't want anyone shooting his eye out.
我可不想看到谁的眼珠被打掉了
Randy, will you eat? There are starving people in China.
兰迪，你吃点好吗？ 还有好多中国人就愁没的吃呢
Mothers know nothing about creeping marauders...
母亲们根本对那些土行孙强盗
burrowing through the snow toward the kitchen...
那些在雪地里打洞偷袭厨房的坏蛋们一无所知
where only you, and you alone, stand between your tiny...
而只有你，你单枪匹马一个人
huddled family and insensate evil.
挡身于你瑟缩成一堆的家人和冷血无情的恶棍之间
Save us, Ralphie! I just knew those bad guys...
救救我们，拉尔菲! 我就知道那帮坏蛋
would be coming for us in the end!
最终会找上门来的!
Don't worry, Dad. As long as I got OI' Blue...
别担心，爸爸，只要我还有这身行头在…
What've we got here, folks?
各位，我们的对头什么来头？
Well, we figure it's Black Bart, Ralph.
哦，我估计是黑巴特，拉尔菲
Well, just me and my trusty old...
好，就凭我和我靠得住的老伙计
Red Ryder carbine-action 200-shot range model air rifle.
瑞得莱德半自动200发射击气枪
Lucky I've got a compass in the stock.
幸运的是在枪托上我们还有个指南针
Well, I think I better have a look here.
好了，我想我最好还是去瞧瞧吧
Oh, no!
哦，不!
It's OI' Blue!
是蓝衫牛仔!
Cheese it, boys!
逃命去吧，小子们!
There's another one! He's a dead-eye, ain't he?
又打中一个! 他可真叫百发百中啊
Okay, Ralphie!
行了，拉尔菲!
You win this time, but we'll be back!
这回算你赢了，但我们还会回来的!
Adi¨®s, Bart.
一路顺风，巴特
But if you do come back, you'll be pushing up daisies!
可你要是胆敢再来，你就准备好棺材吧!
And don't you forget it!
你可千万别忘了!
Well, son, you saved us!
哦，好儿子，你救了我们!
We were goners for sure! And you saved us!
我们明明死定了! 可你救了我们!
Oldsmobile!
该死的奥斯莫比尔!
A pile of junk!
真是一堆垃圾!
That goddamned Olds is froze up again!
该死的老破车又冻住了!
Some men are Baptists, others Catholics. My father was an Oldsmobile man.
有人笃信基督教，有人笃信天主教， 我父亲只信古董老车奥斯莫比尔
That son of a bitch would freeze up in the middle of summer on the Equator!
那狗娘养的三伏天在赤道也会冻住!
Little pitchers...
小水壶…
Hold it!
别吵!
It's a clinker!
什么破玩意儿啊!
That blasted, stupid furnace.
烦人的蠢货炉子
Dadgummit!
去他爸爸的!
Damn skates!
该死的冰鞋!
For Christ's sake, open up the damper, will you?
看在上帝份上，把气门打开吧，好不好？
Who the hell turned it all the way down again?
是谁又妈的把它全关死了？
Blasted!
真讨厌!
In the heat of battle, my father wove a tapestry of obscenity...
在热火朝天的战斗的当儿， 我父亲不觉编织起了一条渎神的挂毯
that as far as we know is still hanging in space over Lake Michigan.
据我所知至今还挂在密歇根湖上空呢
Preparing to go to school was like getting ready...
准备上学的行装
for extended deep-sea diving.
就好比要去做长时间深海潜水一般
Come on, Mom, we're going to be late!
快点啦，妈妈，我们要迟到了!
Just wait, Ralph!
等着，拉尔菲!
My kid brother looked like a tick about to pop.
我弟弟看起来就象一个快要塞爆了的褥套
What?
什么事？
What is it?
怎么了？
I can't put my arms down!
我的胳膊放不下来了!
Well, put your arms down when you get to school.
好了，到了学校你就能把胳膊放下来了
Hey, Flick! Wait up.
嘿，佛理克! 等等我
Wait up!
等等我!
So what are you doing?
你这是干吗去啊？
What does it look like I'm doing? Picking goobers?
你看我象是干吗去的？捡花生吗？
Hey, listen, smart ass. I asked my old man about sticking...
嘿，听着，聪明蛋，我问过我老爸了
your tongue to metal light poles in winter...
就是大冬天舌头会不会粘在金属灯柱上的事
and he says it will freeze right to the pole just like I told you.
他说马上就会冻到灯柱上去的，就跟我说过的一样
Baloney.
胡扯
What would your old man know about anything?
你老爸知道个屁
He knows because he once saw a guy stick his tongue...
他当然知道，他有回看过一个家伙为了打赌
to a railroad track on a bet and the fire department had to come...
把舌头粘在铁轨上了，最后救火队都出动了
to get the guy's tongue off the track because he couldn't get it off.
才把那家伙的舌头从铁轨上弄下来，他自己根本没辙
Come on, guys, wait up!
喂，等等我呀!
Come on, guys!
喂!
I can't get up!
我起不来了!
Help!
救命!
I can't get out! Help me!
我动不了地方了! 帮帮我!
Come on, Flick, wait up for me.
喂，佛理克，等等我
I can't get up!
我起不来了!
Come on.
快来
Get up. Sit up. Come on.
起来，坐起来，快来
You're okay. Come on, let's go.
你没事，快点，我们走吧
Come on, you're all right!
来吧，你什么事都没有!
Miss Shields!
希尔兹小姐来了!
All right, everyone...
好了
take your seats, please.
大家都回座位上去
Good morning, class.
早上好，同学们
Good morning, Miss Shields.
早上好，希尔兹小姐
Open your books to Page 32.
打开书本翻到32页
And as you'll remember, Silas Marner...
你们应该还记得的，《织工马南传》...
You're full of beans and so's your old man.
你大错特错，你老爸也是
Says who?
谁说的？
Says me.
我说的
Well, I double-dare you.
好，我赌你根本不敢
The exact exchange and nuance...
在这种场合措辞的转换及其精微的差别
of phrase in this ritual is very important.
是至关重要的
Are you kidding? Stick my tongue to that stupid pole?
你开玩笑吗？让我用舌头舔这根旗杆？
That's dumb.
这太傻了
That's 'cause you know it will stick!
那就是说你也知道舌头会粘上去的!
You're full of it.
你大错特错了
Well, I double dog-dare you!
那好，我赌你根本他妈的不敢!
Now it was serious. A double dog-dare.
现在问题严重了，根本他妈的不敢
What else was left but a "triple-dare you"?
除了“赌你根本绝对不敢”之外， 还有什么比这更厉害的呢？
And finally, the coup de grace of all dares...
最后，所有赌博里面最致命的一击
the sinister triple dog-dare!
就是赌你根本绝对他妈的不敢!
I triple dog-dare you!
我赌你根本绝对他妈的不敢!
Schwartz created a slight breach of etiquette...
舒瓦兹打破了常规礼节
by skipping the triple-dare and going right for the throat.
他跳过了根本绝对不敢，直奔最后杀招
All right, all right.
好吧，好吧
Go on, smart ass, and do it!
快来啊，聪明蛋，快做吧!
I'm going!
我这不是来了吗!
Flick's spine stiffened, his lips curled in a defiant sneer.
佛理克挺直了背脊，嘴唇咧出了个目空一切的冷笑
There was no going back now.
现在已经无路可退了
This is nothing.
这算什么啊
Stuck? Stuck!
粘住了？粘住了!
Stuck! Stuck!
粘住了! 粘住了!
Jeez!
天哪!
It really works!
这是真的!
Look at him!
瞧他啊!
Ralphie, come back!
拉尔菲，快回来!
Come back! Don't leave me! Come back!
回来! 别把我扔下! 回来!
But the bell rang!
可上课铃响了!
What are we going to do?
我们该怎么办啊？
I don't know! The bell rang!
我不知道! 上课铃响了!
Where's Flick?
佛理克呢？
Has anyone seen Flick?
有人见到佛理克了吗？
Flick? Flick who?
佛理克？ 哪位佛理克啊？
He was at recess, wasn't he?
他刚才下课的时候还在的，对吧？
Ralphie, do you know where Flick is?
拉尔菲，你知道佛理克在哪儿吗？
I said has anyone seen Flick?
我说了有人见到佛理克了吗？
Yes, Esther Jane?
你说，埃丝特・简
Oh, my God!
哦，我的天!
Holy cow, it's the fire department!
哇靠，救火队来了!
Wow, it's the cops!
哇，警察也来了!
Now, I know that some of you put Flick up to this.
听着，我知道是你们当中谁怂恿佛理克去做的
But, he has refused to say who.
可是他不愿说是谁
But those who did it know their blame.
但是谁干的他会受良心谴责的
And I'm sure the guilt you feel...
而且我相信你所受的负罪感
is far worse than any punishment you might receive.
比你可能会受到的任何责罚都要糟糕得多
Now, don't you feel terrible?
听着，你们没感到过意不去吗？
Don't you feel remorse for what you have done?
你们不为做过的事后悔吗？
That's all I'm going to say about poor Flick.
关于可怜的佛理克的事我就想说这么多了
Adults love to say things like that. But kids know better.
大人们就爱这么说，可孩子们要聪明得多
We knew darn well it was always better not to get caught.
我们清楚得不能再清楚了，不被抓住永远是件好事
Now, boys and girls, I'm going to give you an assignment.
听着，孩子们，我要给你们布置一项作业
I want you to write...
我要你们写
a theme.
一篇作文
"What I want for Christmas."
题目是“我想要的圣诞礼物”
The clouds lifted.
拨云见日了
And I want it handed in tomorrow morning...
明天早上就要交…
I saw a faint gleam of light at the other end of...
在厄运之黑洞的尽头
the black cave of doom.
我看到了一线微弱的曙光
I knew that when Miss Shields read my magnificent, eloquent theme...
我知道当希尔兹小姐读到我真切动人的作文
that she would sympathize with my plight...
她会被我身处的困境所打动
and everything would work out, somehow.
而一切都会天遂人意的，以某种方式
Boy, did you see how it stuck?
乖乖，你们看到它是怎么粘上去的吗？
Did it hurt, Flick?
疼不疼啊，佛理克？
No. I never felt a thing.
不疼，我一点感觉都没有
It just caught me off-guard.
我是一时走神才着了道的
You sure were bawling.
你明明大叫来着
I never bawled!
我才没大叫呢!
Baloney.
胡扯
Scut Farkus!
斯卡特・法克斯!
Scut Farkus! What a rotten name. We were trapped.
斯卡特・法克斯! 多可恶的名字，我们落入陷阱了
There he stood, between us and the alley.
他就站在那儿，挡住了我们的去路
Scut Farkus, staring out at us with his yellow eyes.
斯卡特・法克斯，用他的黄眼珠盯着我们看呢
He had yellow eyes! So help me God, yellow eyes.
他有双黄眼珠! 救救我吧，上帝，黄眼珠
Grover Dill, Farkus' crummy little toady.
格拉瓦・迪尔，法克斯的邋遢小走狗
Mean. Rotten.
又坏又可恶
His lips curled over his green teeth.
他咧开嘴露出绿牙在那儿笑呢
Randy lay there like a slug.
兰迪象个鼻涕虫似的躺在那儿
It was his only defense.
这是他唯一的自卫手段
Say "uncle."
叫“叔叔”
Uncle!
叔叔!
Louder!
大声点!
In our world, you were either a bully, a toady...
在我们的世界里，你要么是欺负人的，要么是走狗
or one of the nameless rabble of victims.
要么就是不值一提的广大受欺者中的一员
All right.
好了
Who's next?
下一个该谁了？
In the jungles of kid-dom, the mind switches gears rapidly.
在儿童的世界之林中，我们的脑筋是不会总叮住一处不放的
Weeks ago I had sent away for my Little Orphan Annie...
几周前，我邮购了我的“孤女安妮”神秘会译码笔
Oh, skunked again.
哦，又上当了
No matter. Today I had serious work to do.
没关系，今天我有正经事要办
"What I want for Christmas."
“我想要的圣诞礼物”
"What I want is a Red Ryder BB gun with a compass in the stock...
“我想要的是一支瑞得莱德气枪，枪托上有指南针的...
"and this thing which tells time."
“...还有那个用来计时的玩意儿”
Wow, that's great.
哇，真是太棒了
"I think that everybody should have a Red Ryder BB gun.
“我觉得人人都应该有杆瑞得莱德气枪
"They're very good for Christmas.
“用它来做圣诞礼物再好不过了
"I don't think that a football's a very good Christmas present."
“我不认为橄榄球是件很好的圣诞礼物”
Oh, rarely had the words poured from my penny pencil...
哦，词句从我的便宜铅笔的笔端这么狂热顺畅地流淌出来
with such feverish fluidity.
还真少见呢
I've won! I've won!
我中了! 我中奖了!
The Bumpus hounds.
邦普士家的猎犬
Our hillbilly neighbors, the Bumpuses, had at least...
我们的来自山地的邻居，邦普士一家
785 smelly hound dogs.
至少养了785只臭气熏天的猎犬
And they ignored every other human being on earth but my old man.
而世上人里面除了我老爸，它们谁也看不上眼
I won!
我中了!
What?
中什么了？
A major prize!
中了个大奖!
I won!
我中奖了!
Hey, look at that. Look at that. A Western Union telegram.
嘿，瞧瞧，瞧瞧这个，西部联合公司的电报
Tonight, he's coming tonight. Tonight. Hot damn, tonight!
今晚，今晚就来了，今晚，我的天，就是今晚!
What does this mean here?
这到底什么意思？
It means it's coming tonight!
意思就是说今晚就能到!
I called Ernie McClosky at the freight depot.
我给车站货房的欧尼・麦克洛斯基打过电话了
He said the telegram was late, the prize was already there...
他说电报来晚了，奖品早就运到了
he was going to send it on tonight.
他说他今晚就送过来
Come on. Have a chew, fellas, on me. It's my gift.
来吧，大嚼一顿吧，我请客，算是我给你们的礼物
You know, maybe it'll be one of those Spanish adobe houses down in Coral...
知道吗，奖品有可能是珊瑚道上哪座西班牙砖房...
Serves you right, you smelly buggers.
你是罪有应得，臭狗
Or it could be a bowling alley.
也有可能会是条保龄球道
A guy down in Terre Haute won a bowling alley.
特利豪那儿就有个家伙就赢了一条保龄球道
How are they going to deliver a bowling alley here tonight?
他们该怎么把一条保龄球道在今晚送过来呢？
They could send the deed, for cripesake. I mean...
他们可以把文书送过来，看在上帝份上，我是说…
I didn't expect they were going to send the whole damn bowling alley.
我并不指望他们把该死的整条保龄球道都送过来
Yeah, well. How about eating? I'm starving to death.
是的，好了，能开饭了吗？我都要饿死了
Getting rich is hard work, kid. Come on.
钱可不是那么好赚的啊，孩子们，快来吧
Every family has a kid who won't eat.
每家都有个不爱吃东西的孩子
My kid brother had not eaten voluntarily in over three years.
我弟弟已经有三年没心甘情愿地吃过东西了
Oh, Randy, don't play with your food, eat it!
哦，兰迪，食物不是用来玩的，是用来吃的!
Starving people would be happy to have that.
饿得要死的人要有的吃该多开心啊
Can I have some more red cabbage?
能再给我多来点红甘蓝吗？
Stop playing with your food, or I'll give you something to cry about.
不许再玩了，否则我就要让你吃吃苦头了
You better stop fooling around with it and eat it or you'll be sorry.
你最好别胡闹了马上给我吃，要不你会后悔的
Can I please have some more?
能再给我点吗？
My mother had not had a hot meal for herself in 15 years.
我母亲这15年来就没吃上过一顿热饭
Meatloaf, double beetloaf.
肉饼，还有甜菜饼
I hate meatloaf.
我讨厌肉饼
All right. I'll get that kid to eat.
得了，我会叫那小家伙吃的
Where's my screwdriver and plumber's helper?
我的起子和水拔呢？
I'll open up his mouth and I'll shove it in.
我要撬开他的嘴巴把东西给灌进去
My mother was more subtle.
我母亲的方法就含蓄多了
How do the little piggies go?
咦小猪猪那儿去了？
That's right. Oink, oink.
没错了，呼呼呼呼
Now, show me how the piggies eat. This is your trough.
现在让我瞧瞧小猪猪怎么吃东西的，这就是你的猪槽
Show me how the piggies eat.
让我瞧瞧小猪猪是怎么吃东西的
Be a good boy. Show Mommy how the piggies eat.
做个乖宝宝，让妈咪瞧瞧，小猪猪是怎么吃东西的
Oh, my.
哦，天哪
Mommy's little piggy.
妈咪的小猪猪
It's here.
来了
Are you Parker?
你是帕克吗？
All right, sign here.
好的，在这儿签字吧
Yeah. Well, what is it?
好的，那么这是什么东西？
I don't know.
我不知道
What's in it?
里面装的什么？
Here. Bring it in.
给你.把它送进来吧
Okay, boys. Haul that on in here. Move your tails.
好了，伙计们，把那个抬过来，来活动活动
Bring it right on in. Right here. Bring it ahead. Straight ahead.
直接抬进来吧，就在这儿，往前走，直着走
That's right.
很好
Right.
好的
Here, bring it right in, fellas. That's it. Here we go.
这儿，往前抬就是了，行了，这就到地方了
A little more. Little more.
再过来点，过来一点点
That's it.
好了
Watch the lady.
当心别碰着女人
Thanks a lot, guys.
多谢你们了，伙计们
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Get the crowbar and a hammer, Ralphie. Go on.
把撬棍和榔头拿来，拉尔菲，快去
"Fra-gi-ley."
"Fra-gi-ley."
That must be Italian.
这肯定是意大利文
I think that says "fragile."
我觉得是“小心易碎”
Oh, yeah.
哦，对的
Here we go.
行了
They did a job on this, you know?
他们还真花了一番功夫呢，你们知道吗？
No, here, Ralph, hold this.
不，给你，拉尔菲，拿着这个
There could be anything in there!
这里面放什么东西都有可能啊!
Jesus!
上帝!
Maybe they forgot.
也许他们忘了放货了
It's in there. It's gotta be in there.
就在这里面，应该在里面的
Would you look at that?
你不想瞧瞧这个吗？
What?
什么啊？
What is it?
这是什么啊？
It's a leg!
是条大腿!
But what is it?
可这到底是什么啊？
Well, it's a leg.
唔，就是条大腿
You know, like in a statue.
你知道的，大概是个雕塑吧
Statue?
雕塑？
Yeah, statue!
对，雕塑!
Ralphie!
拉尔菲!
My mother was trying to insinuate herself between us and the statue.
我妈妈试图跻身于我们和雕塑之间
Holy smoke, would you...
哇靠，你不想…
Do you know what this is?
你知道它是什么了吗？
This is a lamp.
它是盏灯
It was indeed a lamp.
这还真的是盏灯呢
Isn't that great? What a great lamp!
这难道不棒吗？多棒的一盏灯啊!
I don't know.
我不知道
Here, hold it. Hold it. Here, go on.
给，拿着，拿着，给你，快呀
The old man's eyes boggled...
老爸双目放光
overcome by art.
整个被这件艺术品迷住了
I know just the place for it.
我知道该把它放哪儿了
Right in the middle of our front room window!
就放在我们正房窗户的正当中
Jesus, God.
天哪，上帝
Honey?
亲爱的？
No. It's all right.
没事，没关系
Let's see...
让我瞧瞧…
This goes to the radio and this goes to the...
这是收音机的，这是…
Well, it's just one too many.
好了，毛病就在加上一个就太多了
Well, let's see.
好，我们试试瞧
The snap of a few sparks, a quick whiff of ozone...
随着几个火花的噼啪和一阵臭氧的气味
and the lamp blazed forth in unparalleled glory.
那盏灯终于大放光芒艳惊四座
Look at that! Will you look at that?
看哪! 你不想瞧瞧吗？
Isn't that glorious?
这有多灿烂啊？
It's indescribably beautiful. It reminds me of the Fourth of July!
真是美得不可思议，它让我想起了7月4号!
Turn off all the lights.
把别的灯都关掉
I wanna see what it looks like from the street.
我要上街对面瞧瞧它看起来如何
I'll go get the dining room.
我去关餐厅的灯
Couldn't we talk this over?
我们能商量商量吗？
Move it a little bit to the right. A little that way.
往右挪一点点，往那边挪一点点
Just a little... More to the right.
就一点点…再往右来点
Yeah. More. That's it. No, stop!
对，再来点，行了，不，别动了!
Right there. That's wonderful.
就是那里，太棒了
Parker, what is that?
帕克，那是什么啊？
Don't bother me now. Can't you see I'm busy?
别打扰我现在，没看到我忙着吗？
Yeah, but what is that?
看到了，可那是什么玩意儿啊？
It's a major award.
是我中的大奖
A major award?
大奖？
Shucks, I wouldn't have known that. It looks like a lamp.
哪有的事，我怎么不知道呢，它看上去象是盏灯
It is a lamp, you nincompoop. But it's a major award.
就是盏灯，你这个笨蛋，可它是我的大奖
I won it.
我赢来的
Damn, hell, you say you won it?
他妈的，见鬼，你说你中了大奖？
Yeah.
没错
Mind power, Sweed, mind power.
智慧的力量，斯威德，智慧的力量
The entire neighborhood was turned on.
现在已经四邻轰动了
You should see what it looks like from out here!
你应该过来瞧瞧它看起来有多美!
It could be seen up and down Cleveland Street.
克利夫兰大街上不是随处都有的看的
The symbol of the old man's victory.
老爸辉煌胜利的标志
Yeah, he won that. It's a major award.
对，是他赢来的，是个大奖
Isn't it about time for somebody's favorite radio program?
是不是快到了谁最爱听的节目的广播时间了？
Holy smokes, it was 6:45.
哇靠，都到6点45了
Only one thing that could've dragged me away...
现在只有一件事
from the soft glow of electric sex gleaming in the window.
才能把我从窗口闪耀的暧昧的电的柔光中拖走
Kids, it's Little Orphan Annie time.
孩子们，这是“孤女安妮”广播的时间了
Brought to you by rich, chocolaty Ovaltine.
由香浓味美的阿华田赞助播出
I could still taste it.
我至今还没忘了它的味道呢
Hey, you turned the light off!
嘿，你把灯给关掉了!
I knew I was handing Miss Shields a masterpiece.
我知道我现在交给希尔兹小姐的是一篇杰作
Maybe Miss Shields, in her ecstasy, would excuse me from theme writing...
兴许希尔兹小姐一高兴
for the rest of my natural life.
就免了我今后所有的作文功课了
You call this a paragraph?
这也叫一段话吗？
Margins! Margins! "F"!
全是空白! 空白! “F”!
My life's work down the drain.
我一生的心血都白费了
A semicolon, you dolt!
分号，你这个笨蛋!
A period.
句号!
"F"!
“F”!
Oh, I should weep if I have to read one more "F"!
如果再让我看到一篇“F”，我就该忍不住眼泪了!
Ralphie Parker.
拉尔菲・帕克
The theme I've been waiting for all my life.
这是我等了一辈子的作文啊
Listen to this sentence.
听听这句
"A Red Ryder BB gun with a compass in the stock...
“一支瑞得莱德气枪，枪托上有指南针的...
"and this thing which tells time."
“...还有那个用来计时的玩意儿”
Poetry.
诗
Sheer poetry.
真是诗啊
Ralph, an "A+."
拉尔菲，给你个“A+”
My Ralph!
我的拉尔菲!
Oh, Ralphie, you've made me proud.
哦，拉尔菲，你真让我感到骄傲
"A+"!
“A+”!
Is there something you want, Ralph?
你有什么事吗，拉尔菲？
I'm just turning in my theme.
我就是来交作文的
Well, you can take your seat now.
好了，你可以回座位了
Take your seat.
回座位吧
Come on, you guys.
你们快点呀
Get in the car. Get in the car.
快上车，快上车
If we don't hurry we're going to miss all the good trees!
不赶紧的话我们就挑不到好树了!
My mother was about to make another brilliant maneuver...
我母亲这就要为那场充满传奇的大腿灯之战
in the legendary battle of the lamp.
再施绝顶妙计
The epic struggle which followed lives in the folklore of Cleveland Street...
这一史诗性的争斗一直在克利夫兰大街众口相传
to this very day.
直至今日
Don't want to waste electricity.
我可不想浪费电
"Don't want to waste electricity."
“我可不想浪费电”
Come on, Ralphie. Get in the car.
快点，拉尔菲，快上车
You folks looking for a tree? We got 300 trees.
你们是在挑树吗？我们这里有300棵呢
This is the Christmas tree emporium of the entire Midwest.
这里是整个中西部的圣诞树大卖场
Now, you ain't gonna find no better tree than this here tree.
听着，你们再找不着比这棵更好的树了
This here tree is built to last.
这棵树种出来就是打算让它活久点的
Ain't no needles coming off this here tree.
这棵树还不掉松针
Okay. Now here's a tree.
好吧，这儿还有棵树
This here is a tree.
就是这棵树
That's a little skimpy in the front.
前面好像长的不是很好
Well, you just put it in the corner.
那么你就把它放墙角好了
Haven't you got a big tree?
你们没有大点的树吗？
Hell, this ain't no tree.
见鬼，这棵简直就不是树
Now here's a tree. This here is a tree.
看这儿还有棵树，就是这棵树
Wait'll the dogs see that one.
狗看到它都会害怕的
Don't you think it's a little large?
是不是有点太大了？
Listen, Christmas only comes once a year. Why not?
听着，一年不就一次圣诞嘛，干吗舍不得呢？
How much?
多少钱？
I'll knock off $2...
我会给你打2块钱折扣
because I can see you're a man who knows his trees.
因为我看得出来你是个行家
This isn't one of those trees that all the needles falls off, is it?
这棵不是那种掉松针的树吧，是不是？
No, that's them balsams.
不是，那些都是冷杉
The old man loved bargaining as much as an Arab trader...
老爸讨价还价的劲头跟阿拉伯商人一样大
and he was twice as shrewd.
而他比他们要精明百倍
You know, Dew Lock just bought one of those brand new...
知道吗，杜洛克刚刚买了棵
green plastic trees.
簇新的绿塑料树
Darn thing looks like it was made out of...
那见鬼的玩意儿看起来就象
green pipe cleaners.
是用绿色烟斗通条做的
This is a very nice tree.
这可是棵好树
I'll throw in some rope and tie it to your car for you.
我会帮你捆好扎到汽车上去的
You got a deal.
成交了
Deal.
成交
Damn it. Blow out!
该死的，胎爆了!
Not again.
又来了
Four minutes!
4分钟!
Time me.
给我计时
Actually, my old man loved it.
实际上我老爸有这嗜好
He always saw himself in the pits at the Indianapolis Speedway...
在印第安纳波利斯500哩跑车大赛的修理间
in the 500.
你经常能见到他的身影
My old man's spare tires were actually only tires...
我老爸的后备胎
in the academic sense.
只是科学意义上的轮胎
They were round. They had once been made of rubber.
它们是圆的，并且是用橡胶造的
Ralphie, why don't you go help your father?
拉尔菲，你干吗不去帮帮你爸爸呢？
Really? Can I?
真的？我能去吗？
Yes.
是的
Watch the traffic, there.
当心那边的车
Okay.
好的
It was the first time that it had been suggested that...
这还是头一回有人告诉我说
I go help my father with anything.
我能帮我父亲干点事
What are you doing here?
你来干吗？
Mom says I should help.
妈妈说我该来帮点忙
Okay, sit down here. Squat down.
好的，坐在这儿，坐下
Yeah, that's it.
对，这就好了
Here. Hold this.
给，拿好
No, not that way. Come on, rat trap, hold it like this.
不，不是那么拿的，看着，小家伙，这么拿
How?
象这样
I want to put the nuts in it. There we are.
我要把螺帽放这里面，好了
There's four of them. And we got it!
一共有四个，都在这里了!
There it is.
在这儿
That son of a gun. I'm gonna get that dirty...
狗娘养的，我要把这个破…
There we go.
这下好了
For one brief moment I saw all the bolts silhouetted...
在那一刹那，迎着车流的光照
against the lights of the traffic. And then they were gone.
我看到了所有螺帽的剪影，然后它们就不见了
Oh, fudge!
哦，见你的大头鬼!
Only I didn't say "fudge."
可我说的偏不是“见你的大头鬼”
I said the word.
我说了那个词
The big one. The queen mother of dirty words.
那个要命的词，脏话里面最脏的那个
The "f, dash, dash, dash" word.
那个“×你×”的词
What did you say?
你刚才说什么？
That's what I thought you said.
我想我知道你说了什么
Get in the car.
给我上车去
Go on.
快去
It was all over. I was dead.
全完了，我死定了
What would it be? The guillotine? Hanging?
会是什么死法呢？上断头台？绞刑架？
The chair? The rack? The Chinese water torture?
坐电椅？上刑具？蹲水牢？
Mere child's play compared to what surely awaited me.
所有这些跟我就要受的罪相比不过儿戏罢了
Everything go all right?
都搞定了？
Eight minutes.
8分钟
Do you know what your son just said?
你知道你儿子刚才说什么了吗？
No. What?
不知道，他说什么了？
I'll tell you what he said. Randy!
我会告诉你他说什么的，兰迪!
Ralphie!
拉尔菲!
Over the years, I got to be quite a connoisseur of soap.
经过这么多年，我也该成为一个肥皂鉴赏家了
My personal preference is for Lux, but I found Palmolive had a nice...
我个人偏爱力士，但我发现棕榄有一种
piquant, after-dinner flavor.
好闻，刺激，餐后的香味
Heady, but with just a touch of mellow smoothness.
有点冲，但还带那么一点甜香醇美
Lifebuoy, on the other hand...
卫宝呢，那就…
You ready to tell me?
你打算告诉我了吗？
All right. Where did you hear that word?
好的，你是从哪儿听到那个词的？
Now I had heard that word at least 10 times a day from my old man.
我每天至少听老爸说10遍那个词
My father worked in profanity the way...
我父亲用起亵渎神灵的话
other artists might work in oils or clay.
就象别的艺术家用油彩或粘土那么熟
It was his true medium. A master.
那才是属于他的材料，他是个大师
But I chickened out. And I blurted out...
可我已经吓坏了，所以脱口而出的是
the first name that came to mind.
第一个跑进我脑海里的名字
Schwartz!
舒瓦兹!
I see.
明白了
Hello, Mrs. Schwartz? Yes, I'm fine.
喂，舒瓦兹太太吗？是的，我很好
Mrs. Schwartz, do you know what Ralph just said?
舒瓦兹太太，你知道拉尔菲刚说了什么吗？
No.
不是
He said...
他说的是…
Not that!
不是吧!
Yes, that.
是的，就是那个
Do you know where he heard it?
你知道他从哪儿听到的吗？
Probably from his father.
兴许从他爸爸那儿吧
No! He heard it from your son!
不! 他从你儿子嘴里听到的!
What?
什么？
What'd I do, Mom?
我干什么了，妈妈？
Why? I didn't do nothing!
为什么？我什么也没干呀!
Another shot of mysterious, inexorable, official justice.
又一个神秘，无情，权威的公义的例子
Rinse out and go to bed. Am I glad you finished your homework!
漱口上床，你做完了功课我很高兴!
Get right into bed, and I don't want to see any lights on.
马上就上床，我不想看见灯还亮着
You are being punished, so no comic book reading!
你正在受罚，所以漫画书不许看了!
I'll come in, and if any lights are on...
我会进去检查的，要是灯还亮着的话…
Don't you give me that look! You're gonna get it!
不许这么瞧我! 你找打吗!
Three blocks away, Schwartz was getting his.
距此三个街区，舒瓦兹正挨着揍呢
There has never been a kid who didn't believe...
所有的孩子都有点相信但又很难不信
vaguely but insistently, that he would be stricken blind...
他们不到21岁就会双目失明
before he reached 21. And then they'd be sorry.
到那时他们就该追悔莫及了
Why, it's Ralph!
啊，是拉尔菲!
Well, come on in, Ralph. Where've you been?
好的，进来吧，拉尔菲，你上哪儿去了？
Why, he's carrying a cane!
啊，他拿着根拐杖!
What is it, Ralph? What happened?
怎么了，拉尔菲？出什么事了？
Why, he's blind!
啊，他瞎了!
Blind? Oh, my God!
瞎了？哦，我的天!
Ralph, is it something we did?
拉尔菲，这是我们造成的吗？
What brought you to this lonely state?
是什么使得你陷于这么孤苦的境地？
Ralph, please tell us no matter how it hurts. What did we do?
拉尔菲，请告诉我们吧，不管有多痛苦，我们都干了什么啊？
Look, I can't.
瞧，我不能说
Please, Ralph. I must know what we did.
求你了，拉尔菲，我一定要知道我们都干了些什么
What brought you to this?
是什么把你害成这样的？
Soap poisoning.
肥皂中毒
Oh, how could we do it?
哦，当初我们怎么会那么干的啊？
I'll manage to get along, somehow.
我会挺过去的，以某种方式
I'll never forgive myself.
我永远不会原谅我自己
Thanks, Mom.
谢谢你，妈妈
I told you not to use Lifebuoy.
我跟你说过不要用卫宝的
I feel awful!
我感觉糟透了!
Thank you, Heather.
谢谢你，希瑟
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Thank you, Flick.
谢谢你，佛理克
Merry Christmas, Miss Shields.
圣诞快乐，希尔兹小姐
I just thought that you'd be getting tired of the same old stuff.
我只是想老是那么几样东西你可能都厌了
Yes, truly, a little bribe never hurts.
是的，一点不假，小小的贿赂是没坏处的
Well, thank you very much, Ralph.
哦，非常感谢你，拉尔菲
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Happy New Year.
新年快乐
You can take your seat now, Ralph.
你可以回座位了，拉尔菲
The weeks of drinking gallons of Ovaltine, in order to get...
几周内狂喝阿华田
the Ovaltine inner seal to send off for my Little Orphan Annie...
就为了得到它的内衬密封圈
secret decoder pen, was about to pay off.
好邮出换取“孤女安妮”神秘译码笔，终于算没白费功夫
I got it. "Master Ralph Parker."
信来了，“拉尔菲・帕克台鉴”
My decoder pen!
我的译码笔!
All right!
太好了!
"Be it known to all that Ralph Parker is hereby appointed...
“敬请昭告天下兹特委以拉尔菲・帕克
"a member of the Little Orphan Annie secret circle and...
“‘孤女安妮’神秘会会员之身份
"is entitled to all the honors and benefits occurring thereto."
“并从此尽享相应之荣耀及利益”
Signed, Little Orphan Annie.
签字，孤女安妮
Countersigned, Pierre Andre!
副署，皮埃尔・安德鲁!
In ink!
是亲笔签名!
Honors and benefits. Already at the age of nine.
荣誉和利益，才九岁就能享有这些了
Come on. Let's get on with it.
快点，快开始吧
I don't need all that jazz about smugglers and pirates.
我可不想听那些关于走私犯和海盗的废话
Listen tomorrow night for the concluding adventure of...
明晚请接着收听“黑海盗船”历险记的大结局
The Black Pirate Ship. Now it's time...
现在
for Annie's secret message for you members of the secret circle.
是对神秘会会员播出安妮秘信的时候了
Remember, kids, only members of...
请记住，孩子们，只有安妮神秘会的会员
Annie's secret circle can decode Annie's secret message.
才能解开这条安妮秘信的密码
Remember, Annie is depending on you.
记住，安妮的命运就掌握在你们手中了
Set your pins to B-2.
请把指针转到B-2的位置
Here is the message.
下面就是秘信的内容
12. 11. 2...
12、11、2…
I am in my first secret meeting.
这是我生平头一遭神秘集会
...25. 14. 11. 18.
...25、14、11、18
16. 23...
16、23...
Pierre was in great voice tonight.
皮埃尔今晚的声音真动听
I could tell that tonight's message was really important.
我可以看出今晚的密信万分重要
...3. 25.
...3.25
That's a message from Annie herself. Remember, don't tell anyone.
这是来自安妮本人的秘信，记住，别向任何人泄露
Ninety seconds later I'm in the only room in the house...
一分半钟之后我已经身处这房子里唯一一处
where a boy of nine can sit in privacy and decode.
一个九岁大的孩子能独自坐着破译密码的地方了
Ah! "B." I went to the next.
啊哈! “B”，我再看下一个
"E." The first word is "be"!
“E”，第一个词是“be”!
"S." It was coming easier now. "U."
“S”，现在越来越顺手了，“U”
Come on, Ralphie! I gotta go.
快点，拉尔菲! 我要尿尿
I'll be right down, Ma.
我马上就下来，妈
Gee whiz.
我的天哪
"T. O."
“T”“O”
"Be sure to." Be sure to what?
“Be sure to”（一定要），一定要干吗？
What was Little Orphan Annie trying to say? Be sure to what?
“孤女安妮”到底想说什么？一定要干吗？
Ralphie! Randy has got to go! Will you please come out?
拉尔菲! 兰迪快憋不住了! 你能让个位吗？
All right, Ma! I'll be right out!
好的，妈! 我马上就好!
I was getting closer now.
我就快知道答案了
The tension was terrible. What was it?
空气紧张得可怕，这到底说的什么呢？
The fate of the planet may hang in the balance.
整个星球的命运也许正悬于一发
Ralphie! Randy's gotta go!
拉尔菲! 兰迪快憋不住了!
I'll be right out, for crying out loud!
我马上就出来，拜托你好不好!
Almost there! My fingers flew.
就快出来了! 我的手指在飞速转动
My mind was a steel trap.
我的思维快如闪电
Every pore vibrated.
每个毛孔都在颤动
It was almost clear.
差不多全明白了
Yes!
好了!
Ovaltine?
阿华田？
A crummy commercial?
又一个廉价广告？
Son of a bitch!
狗娘养的!
I went out to face the world again.
我出了房间再次面对现实
Wiser.
长了一智
Red cabbage?
又是红甘蓝？
No, that's for tomorrow night. You love red cabbage, Ralphie.
不，这是明晚吃的，你爱吃红甘蓝的，拉尔菲
You filthy system!
这套脏兮兮的破玩意儿!
I hate it!
我恨透了!
Schmucker! Smelly watt-buster!
笨蛋! 臭气熏天的混蛋!
What happened next was a family controversy for years.
接下来发生的事多年来在这个家里莫衷一是
What was that? What happened?
怎么了？发生什么事了？
What happened?
发生什么事了？
What broke?
什么打破了？
I don't know what happened.
我也不知道怎么回事
I was watering my plant and...
我正在给花浇水…
I broke your lamp.
我把你的灯打破了
Don't you touch that!
你别碰它!
You were always jealous of this lamp.
你一直在嫉妒这盏灯
Jealous of a plastic leg?
嫉妒这条塑料大腿？
Jealous!
嫉妒!
Jealous because I won.
因为我中了奖所以你嫉妒
That's ridiculous! Jealous?
太可笑了! 我嫉妒？
Jealous of what?
嫉妒什么？
That is...
这是个…
the ugliest lamp I have ever seen in my entire life!
我这辈子见到的最丑陋的灯!
Now it was out.
终于说出口了
Get the glue.
拿胶水来
We're out of glue.
我们的胶水用完了
You used up all the glue on purpose!
你是故意把胶水用光的!
The old man stood quivering with fury...
老爸站在那儿气得浑身哆嗦
stammering as he tried to come up with a real crusher.
结结巴巴的仿佛他马上要说出句置人于死地的话似的
All he got out was:
可他说出来的却是:
Not a finger!
一根手指头也不许碰!
With as much dignity as he could muster...
用尽了所有的尊严
the old man gathered up the sad remains...
老爸搜集起了他引以为荣的大奖
of his shattered major award.
的可怜的碎片
Later that night, alone in the backyard...
当晚后半夜，独自在后院
he buried it next to the garage.
他把它们埋在车库旁边了
Now I could never be sure...
现在我已经说不准了
but I thought that I heard the sound of taps being played...
不过我想当时我听到了丧号的声音
gently.
轻轻地奏着
Know what I'm getting my old man for Christmas?
知道圣诞我要送老爸什么吗？
What?
什么？
A rose that squirts.
会喷水的玫瑰
People come to smell it, it squirts them.
有人凑近闻它香味的时候，它就喷他们一脸
I'm getting my old man a Flit gun.
我要送我老爸一把水枪
A Flit gun?
水枪？
Stop right there!
给我站住别动!
Ordinarily, if Dill so much as said "hi" to you, you felt great...
一般来说，如果迪尔只是跟你说声嗨
warm inside. But mostly he just hit you in the mouth.
你会觉得心里暖乎乎的，但多数情况下， 他只会一拳打在你的嘴上
I can't now, Grover. I've gotta go see Miss Shields.
我现在不能在这儿多待，格拉瓦，我得去找希尔兹小姐
Hey, come here! Get over here!
嘿，过来! 给我过来!
Come on, you! Hey, come here!
快来，你! 嘿，给我过来!
You! Come here!
你! 过来!
Who, me?
谁？我？
No, your Aunt Tilly.
不，是你蒂莉阿姨
Yeah, you. Get over here!
对，就是你，给我过来!
I left Flick to certain annihilation.
我把佛理克扔下让他活受罪去了
But BB gun mania knows no loyalties.
可狂热的气枪迷是不讲义气的
Uncle! Uncle!
叔叔! 叔叔!
All right, class.
好了，同学们
I have your Christmas themes for you.
我这就把你们的以圣诞为题的作文发下来
I'm pleased.
我很满意
In general, you did very well.
总的来说，你们都写得不错
However, I was disappointed in the margins.
但是，我对文章的字数很不满意
This is it.
就是它了
"C+"? No, it can't be.
“C+”？不，不可能的
C+?
C+？
C+!
C+!
Oh, no!
哦，不!
"You'll shoot your eye out"?
“你会把你的眼珠射出来的”？
My mother must have gotten to Miss Shields.
我母亲肯定和希尔兹串通一气了
There could be no other explanation.
否则还能有什么别的解释呢
You'll shoot your eye out. You'll shoot your eye out.
你会把你的眼珠射出来的，你会把你的眼珠射出来的
Was there no end to this conspiracy of irrational prejudice...
对瑞得莱德和他忠诚的调解人毫无道理的偏见
against Red Ryder and his peacemaker?
是不是永远没完没了呢？
These multiplication questions were most missed in our last math test.
上次数学测验这道乘法题大多数人都做错了
Would you answer in unison, please?
大家能齐声说出答案吗？
I was surrounded by happier kids who were all going to get...
我被包围在一群开心的
what they wanted for Christmas.
即将得到他们想要的圣诞礼物的孩子们中
...fifty-six.
...56
Hey, four-eyes!
嘿，四眼!
How'd you like your snowball sandwich?
雪球三明治的味道怎么样？
Maybe you'd like another one!
也许你还想吃一个!
Listen, jerk.
听着，蠢蛋
When I tell you to come, you better come!
我叫你过来的时候，你最好马上过来!
What? Are you going to cry now?
什么？你要哭鼻子了吗？
Come on, cry baby, cry for me. Come on.
来啊，哭鼻子的小毛孩，哭着找我吧，来啊
Cry!
哭呀!
Deep in the recesses of my brain...
在我的脑海里什么地方
a tiny red-hot little flame began to grow.
一个小小的炽热的火苗开始熊熊燃烧起来了
Something had happened.
什么东西突然爆发了
A fuse blew and I had gone out of my skull.
保险丝烧断了，我完全失去了理智
I'm telling my dad!
我要去告诉我爸爸!
Hey, Ralphie!
嘿，拉尔菲!
Beat him up! Beat him up!
揍他! 揍他!
Did you hear what he said?
你听到他说的话了吗？
I have since heard of people under...
我后来才听说被极度压抑的人
extreme duress speaking in strange tongues.
是会说出很多奇怪的话来的
I became conscious that a steady torrent of obscenities...
我开始意识到各式各样的谩骂和诅咒的急流
and swearing of all kinds was pouring out of me as I screamed.
在我尖声叫嚷的时候正从我口中飞泄而出
Ralphie!
拉尔菲!
We're going home. Come on.
我们回家吧，走吧
Calm down. Come on in here, Ralph.
好了不哭，进来吧，拉尔菲
Put your head down in here.
把头低下来
Come on, get down in here.
来吧，伸到这儿来
Settle down.
好了不哭
I want you to go in there and lie down in your room for a while.
我想让你进屋去躺一会儿
Ralphie, just settle down.
拉尔菲，好了不哭
Here, dry off.
来，擦擦干
All right, calm down.
好了，不哭
All right. Now go lie down.
好了，现在去躺会儿吧
The light was getting purple and soft outside.
外面已是万家灯火
Almost time for my father to come home from work.
差不多到了父亲下班回家的时候了
What's the matter? What you crying for?
怎么了？你哭什么呀？
Daddy's going to kill Ralphie.
爸爸会杀了拉尔菲的
No, he's not.
不，他不会的
Yes, he is, too.
会的，他会的
I promise you Daddy is not going to kill Ralphie.
我向你保证爸爸不会杀了拉尔菲的
Why don't you come on out of there?
你干吗不从里面出来呢？
Would you like some milk?
想喝点牛奶吗？
You would?
要是吗？
Here you go.
给你
All right?
好了吧？
I'll see you later? Okay. Bye.
等会儿再见？好的，等会儿见
I heard the car roar up the driveway, and a wave of terror broke over me.
我听到汽车在车道上轰鸣的声音，一阵恐惧的浪潮向我袭来
He'll know what I said, the awful things that I said.
他会知道我都说了些什么的，我说的那些肮脏透顶的话
Get out of here!
给我滚开!
Go on home, you mangy mutts. Get out of here, you rotten, filthy...
赶紧回家，你们这些脏狗，滚开，你们这些混蛋，坏种…
Hey, Bumpus!
嘿，邦普士!
Get over here and get your stinking dogs!
给我过来把你的臭狗牵走!
Hey, come on, what's for dinner? I'm starving to death.
嘿，快点，晚饭吃什么？我都快饿死了
Well, what happened today?
那么今天有什么事吗？
Where's your glasses?
你的眼镜呢？
Did you lose your glasses again?
你是不是又把眼睛给丢了？
Ralphie.
拉尔菲
Remember, you left these on the radio again.
记住了，你又把这个丢在收音机上了
Now try not to do that anymore.
记住别再忘了
So what else happened today?
那么今天还有什么事？
Nothing much.
没什么特别的
Ralphie had a fight.
拉尔菲跟人打了一架
A fight?
打架？
What kind of a fight?
打的什么架？
You know how boys are.
你知道男孩们的德行
I gave him a talking to.
我已经教训过他了
I see that the Bears are playing Green Bay on Sunday.
我看到周日狗熊队和绿湾队有场比赛
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的
Zudock's got tickets. I wish I had.
祖道克已经搞到票了，真希望我也有张
He'll freeze his keister off out there.
他在那儿会把屁股冻掉的
I slowly began to realize I was not about to be destroyed.
我逐渐开始意识到我的末日已经不会马上就来了
The Chicago Bears.
芝加哥狗熊队
The terror of the midway.
拦路猛虎
From then on, things were different between me and my mother.
从这时候开始，我和我母亲的关系和以前不一样了
More like the Chicago Chipmunks, maybe.
也许该叫他们芝加哥花栗鼠
But Bears, never.
叫狗熊，得了吧
Strange.
奇怪
Even something as monumental as "The Scut Farkus Affair"...
就连"斯卡特・法克斯事件"这么不朽的传奇
as it came to be known...
这一点已经逐渐为人所知了
was pushed out of my mind as I struggled for a way out...
在我奋力挣脱那牢不可破的气枪之网的时候
of the impenetrable BB gun web...
也被我完全抛在脑后了
in which my mother had me trapped.
而这网正是我母亲亲手编织的
Santa!
圣诞老人!
Yeah, I'll ask Santa.
对，我要去向圣诞老人要
Of course! Santa.
当然了! 就找圣诞老人
The big man. The head honcho.
他是头上面的头，老板里面的老板
The connection.
孩子的代言人
My mother had slipped up this time.
我母亲这回就认栽吧
Mickey!
米老鼠!
The store's going to close soon and Santa will be gone.
商店马上就要关门了，圣诞老人也要走了
Ralphie, Santa's not going anyplace. Just be still!
拉尔菲，圣诞老人哪儿也不会去的，别吵
Mom, this is just the same old dumb parade as last year.
妈妈，这个游行跟去年的一模一样，蠢得要死
Ralphie, will you please calm down.
拉尔菲，你能不能安静点
Mom--
妈妈…
Hush!
别吵!
Shut up, Ralphie!
闭嘴，拉尔菲!
There he is!
他在那儿!
Santa!
圣诞老人!
Have you been a good boy? Have you?
你是不是个乖孩子？是不是？
Can we go now? Can we go?
现在我们能走了吗？能走了吗？
Yes, we can go now.
好的，我们现在就走
Come on, Ralphie.
来吧，拉尔菲
Merry Christmas!
圣诞快乐!
Come on, Randy, hurry up.
快，兰迪，快点
Ralphie, look over there.
拉尔菲，看那边
See, the line's not so long. Get in it.
瞧，队不算长，快去排吧
Take Randy's hand and hold on to him. We'll see you later, okay?
抓牢兰迪的手别丢下他，我们等会再来找你们，好吗？
Stay together, you hear? And don't get lost.
别走散了，听到了吗？ 别走丢了
Come on.
快来
Let's go.
走啦
Young man.
年轻人
Hey, kid.
嘿，孩子
Just where do you think you're going?
你知道你要做什么吗？
We're going up to see Santa.
我们要上去见圣诞老人
The line ends here. It begins there.
这是队头，队尾在那边
Merry Christmas!
圣诞快乐!
Come on, come up, boys and girls. Hurry up.
快，快上来，孩子们，快点
Come on.
来吧
The line waiting to see Santa stretched all the way back to Terre Haute!
等待圣诞老人接见的队列一直排到了特利豪!
And I was at the end of it.
而我排在队列的最后
I like Santa.
我喜欢圣诞老人
Let's face it. Most of us were scoffers.
让我们面对现实吧，这里大多数人都扮演了小丑的角色
Moments before zero hour, it did not pay to take chances.
可在零点钟声没敲响之前，总该碰碰运气
The chocolate snowman eats little boys.
巧克力雪人是要吃小男孩的
My pretty...
我的心肝…
What a tasty little boy.
多美味的小男孩啊
Don't bother me. I'm thinking.
别烦我，我在想事呢
I like The Wizard of Oz.
我喜欢“奥兹国历险记”
I like the Tin Man.
我喜欢里面的铁皮人
If Higbee thinks I'm working one minute past 9:00, he can kiss my foot.
要是黑比以为过了9点我会给他们多干一分钟，等下辈子吧
Come on up on Santa's lap.
来，坐到圣诞老人的腿上来
There's a wet one. And what's your name, little boy?
一个湿乎乎的小人，你叫什么名字，小家伙？
Billy.
比利
Come on, Randy.
快，兰迪
And what do you want for Christmas, Billy? A toy truck?
你想要什么圣诞礼物啊，比利？一辆玩具车？
Get him off my lap.
把他抱下去吧
Quick, get me a towel.
快点，给我条毛巾
I hate the smell of tapioca.
我讨厌木薯的味道
Attention shoppers! It is now 9:00 and our store is closing.
注意顾客们! 现在已经9点钟了，店门马上就要关了
9:00! Great Scott! The store is gonna close!
9点了! 天哪! 商店马上就要关门了!
Santa can't wait all night.
圣诞老人不可能整晚都守在这儿的
Come on up on Santa's lap.
坐到圣诞老人的腿上来
Get moving, kid.
快走，孩子
Quit dragging your feet.
别磨磨蹭蹭的
Get him out of here.
把他送走
Come on, kid.
快来，孩子
Come on up.
快上来
And what's your name, little boy?
你叫什么名字啊，小家伙？
Hey, kid, hurry up, the store's closing!
嘿，孩子，快点，店门马上就要关了!
Listen, little boy, we got a lot of people waiting here, so get going!
听着，小家伙，有好多人在等着呢，就快点吧!
What do you want for Christmas, little boy?
你想要什么圣诞礼物啊，小家伙？
My mind had gone blank.
我的思想一片空白
Frantically I tried to remember what it was I wanted.
我疯狂地想回忆起我到底要什么
I was blowing it, blowing it.
我真糟糕，太糟糕了
How about a nice football?
一个漂亮的橄榄球怎么样？
Football. What's a football?
橄榄球？橄榄球是什么啊？
Without conscious will, my voice squeaked out:
毫无意识地，我脱口而出
Football.
橄榄球
Okay, get him out of here.
好了，把他送走吧
A football! Oh, no. What was I doing?
橄榄球，哦不，我在干吗啊？
Wake up, stupid, wake up!
醒醒，笨蛋，醒醒!
I want an official Red Ryder carbine-action 200-shot...
我想要一支正牌瑞得莱德半自动200发射击气枪
You'll shoot your eye out, kid.
你会把你的眼珠射出来的
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
I'll see you in Oz, folks.
奥兹国再见吧，各位
Well, did you see Santa Claus?
好了，你们见过圣诞老人了吗？
Did you tell him what you wanted for Christmas?
你告诉他你想要什么圣诞礼物了吗？
Did he ask you if you'd been a good boy all year?
他问你这一年是不是一直是个乖孩子了吗？
No.
没有
Don't worry, he knows.
别担心，他都知道的
He always knows.
他什么都知道
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Okay, down you go.
好了，下去吧
Bye, Chris.
再见，克莉丝
That's fine.
太棒了
Now wait a minute. All right. Plug her in!
等一下，好了，插上插头吧!
Well, the green string is out.
哦，绿色灯串没亮
No, the green is on. It's the blue that's out.
绿的亮了，没亮的是蓝色的
Oh, don't tell me what color it is.
哦，别告诉我它是什么颜色
I'm not color blind.
我又不是色盲
I'm not color blind, either.
我也不是色盲
There, see, I told you it was green.
好了，瞧，我告诉你是绿的
Hold it! Don't anybody move!
别动! 谁也别动!
Hold it right there!
就站在原地!
A fuse is out.
保险丝爆了
The old man could replace fuses quicker than a jackrabbit on a date.
老爸换起保险丝来比赶约会的长耳朵兔还要快
He bought them by the gross.
他一买就是一大把
Oh, Ralph.
哦，拉尔菲
My, isn't that pretty?
我的天，多漂亮啊!
That son of a gun.
狗娘养的
Yeah. No.
是啊.  不
That star is crooked.
那颗星有点歪
That star is perfectly straight.
那颗星正得很啊
Oh, you've got to be careful.
哦，你得当心点
I am.
我知道
It's just... Let me get it fixed. That's all right.
不过…让我把它弄弄好，这下好了
Perfect.
太好了
Oh, goodness, look at the time.
哦，天哪，看都几点了
I hope Santa hasn't had to pass up this house...
但愿圣诞老人还没从这屋顶上就这么走过去了
just because some boys weren't in bed when he came by.
就因为有的孩子在他经过的时候还没上床
I thought I heard Santa's sleigh bells...
我想我刚才听到圣诞老人的雪撬铃声了
a little while ago, going up the other side of the street.
从街那头传过来的
All right, you two, upstairs.
好了，你们两个，快上楼
Go on the double, on the double.
加快脚步，加快
Okay, let's get them.
好了，我们去拿东西吧
Randy, come on! Get up, Randy!
兰迪，快来! 起床吧，兰迪!
Santa Claus had come!
圣诞老人来过了!
Wow! A truck! That's mine!
哇! 一辆卡车! 是我的!
Wow, look over here! That's mine!
哇，快来看啊! 这也是我的!
What's in here?
这里面什么东西？
It's hard.
硬硬的
Fire truck. Oh boy, that's mine!
救火车，哦天哪，也是我的!
Does this raise?
这个能升起来吗？
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas, you two.
圣诞快乐，你们两个
Randy, no. Wait for Christmas to start, honey.
兰迪，不要拆，等圣诞节正式开始了再动手,亲爱的
I want to play Santa!
我要当圣诞老人!
Well, wait a minute, Randy.
哦，等一下，兰迪
He played Santa last year, didn't he?
去年就是他当圣诞老人的，是吗？
Ralphie, you play Santa this time.
拉尔菲，这次你来当圣诞老人
Come on, Ralphie.
快点，拉尔菲
Who should I start with?
现在我应该做什么？
Well, give Randy a present.
那就从给兰迪一件礼物开始吧
And, I think I see Aunt Clara's gift to you right over there.
我想我看到克莱尔阿姨送给你的礼物了，就在那边
She always sends you such wonderful presents.
她总是送你那么好的礼物
Give me mine, Ralphie! Come on.
给我礼物吧，拉尔菲! 快啊
Christmas had come. Officially. We plunged into the cornucopia...
圣诞算是正式来到了，我们一头扎进了大获丰收的喜悦
quivering with desire and the ecstasy of unbridled avarice.
无穷的欲望和不受制约的贪婪令我们欣喜若狂，浑身发颤
Didn't I get a tie this year?
这不，又是一条领带？
A zeppelin!
齐帕林飞艇!
A can of Simonize.
一罐西蒙奈兹蜡
Ralphie, what did Aunt Clara give you? Show everybody.
拉尔菲，克莱尔阿姨送你什么了？给大家瞧瞧
I don't want to.
我不想
Ralphie, show everybody what Aunt Clara gave you.
拉尔菲，让大家瞧瞧克莱尔阿姨送你的是什么
Aunt Clara had for years labored under the delusion that...
好多年来克莱尔阿姨不但当我永远4岁
I was not only perpetually four years old, but also a girl.
而且还是个女孩子
She just always gives you the nicest things, Ralphie.
她总是把她亲手做的最好的东西送给你，拉尔菲
Oh, isn't that sweet?
哦，这多可爱啊
Ralph, go upstairs and try it on you--
拉尔菲，上楼去穿上它
I don't want to!
我不想去!
Go upstairs right now and try on that present!
马上上楼把阿姨送你的礼物穿上!
She went to all that trouble to make it! Now go on.
这可是她不辞劳苦为你做的! 现在快去!
While Ralphie is changing, I'm going to play Santa Claus.
拉尔菲换衣服的时候，我来当圣诞老人
Now, let me see what can I find.
现在，看我能找到什么
I see something! Randy.
我找到了! 兰迪
This is for you, honey.
这是你的，亲爱的
And this is for Daddy.
这是爸爸的
Here.
给
From me to you.
我给你的
Thanks a lot.
太谢谢了
I wonder what it could be?
我很想知道会是什么呢？
Only one way to find out, isn't there?
想知道只有一个办法，对吧？
Well, it's a blue ball!
哦，是个蓝球!
It's a bowling ball.
是个保龄球
Thank you, darling.
谢谢，亲爱的
Do you like it?
你喜欢吗？
Yes, very much. Very much.
是的，很喜欢，很喜欢
Ralphie.
拉尔菲
We're waiting.
我们在等着呢
Oh, come on, Mom.
哦，拜托，妈妈
Right now!
马上下楼!
Lmmediately my feet began to sweat as those two fluffy little bunnies...
在那两只毛绒绒的小兔儿鞋里我的脚立刻就开始冒汗了
with the blue button eyes stared sappily up at me.
它们的蓝扣子眼睛还一个劲傻傻地盯着我看
Come down here so I can see you better.
下来点让我看清楚点
I just hoped Flick would never spot them...
我只希望佛理克永远也不会看到这身衣服
as the word of this humiliation could easily make life...
因为我这么丢人现眼的话一旦传出去
at Warren G. Harding School a veritable hell.
我在沃伦哈丁高校的日子就会成为人间炼狱了
Isn't that cute?
这有多可爱啊
That is the most precious thing I've ever seen in my life.
这是我这辈子看到的最稀罕的东西了
Shut up, Randy.
不许笑，兰迪
He looks like a deranged Easter bunny.
他看起来就象个发了疯的复活节兔子
He does not!
没有的事!
He does, too.
就是的
He looks like a pink nightmare.
他看起来就象个粉红色的恶梦
Are you happy wearing that?
穿这个你很开心吗？
Do you want to take it off?
想不想把它脱下来？
You tell the kid to take it off.
你叫孩子把它脱了吧
You'll only wear it when Aunt Clara visits. Go on and take it off.
克莱尔阿姨来的时候才穿，去把它脱了吧
Take it off!
脱掉!
My God, will you look at that mess?
我的天，你看看这乱的
Who's going to clean the papers up?
谁来把那些废纸收拾掉？
Not me.
别找我
Randy did it last year.
去年是兰迪做的
Well, he can do it again.
唔，他还可以再做一次嘛
You know, this wine is not bad. It's not good either, but...
知道吗，酒不是个坏东西，可也不是好东西，但是…
You want a sip?
你想尝一口吗？
No, you don't.
不，你不能喝
Did you have a nice Christmas?
你这个圣诞过得开心吗？
Yeah, pretty nice.
是的，还不错
Did you get everything you wanted?
你想要的都得到了吗？
Well, almost.
嗯，差不多吧
Almost?
差不多？
Well, that's life.
嗯，生活就是这样的
Well, there's always next Christmas.
明年还有圣诞嘛
That's funny.
真有趣
What's that over there behind the desk?
那边在桌子后面的是什么？
Where?
哪里？
Behind the desk, against the wall over there.
桌子后面，那边靠着墙放着的
Why don't you go check it out?
你干吗不过去瞧瞧呢？
What did we put over there, honey?
我们把什么放那儿了，亲爱的？
Santa Claus probably put it.
也许是圣诞老人放的
Oh, it was beautiful. I could hardly wait to try it out.
哦，真是绝品，我已经急不可待要去试枪了
Do you know how to load it?
你知道子弹怎么装吗？
That's right.
没错
Be careful.
当心点
Don't. They run all over.
别，会滚得满地都是的
Close her up. Close it up.
把枪膛合上，合上它
Can I try it out, Ma? Can I?
我能去试试枪吗，妈？行吗？
Sure.
当然了
Okay.
好吧
But outside.
可得去屋外
I still say those things are dangerous.
我还要说这种东西太危险
Put on your galoshes and your coat. It's cold out.
把套鞋和大衣穿上，外面很冷
I had one when I was eight years old.
我8岁的时候也有一支
What if he hurts himself? Ralphie, your coat!
要是他伤着自己了怎么办？拉尔菲，你的大衣!
Don't shoot any animals or birds!
- 不许射动物或者小鸟!
Except the Bumpuses' dogs!
邦普士家的狗除外!
Be careful, Ralphie!
当心点，拉尔菲!
Now it is well known throughout the Midwest that the old man...
我老爸嗜鸡如命
is a turkey junkie.
现在已经是整个中西部家喻户晓的事了
A bona fide garley turkicanus freak. A few days before Christmas...
一个不折不扣的火鸡大饕
his eyes would begin to gleam with a wild and ravenous light.
从圣诞前几天开始疯狂而饥渴的光芒就在他的双眼闪烁
Okay, Black Bart, now you get yours.
好了，黑巴特，现在拿命来吧
Oh, my God! I shot my eye out!
哦，天哪! 我把我的眼珠射出来了!
You'll shoot your eye out, kid.
你会把你的眼珠射出来的，孩子
You'll shoot your eye out, you'll shoot your eye out!
你会把你的眼珠射出来的，你会把你的眼珠射出来的!
Ralphie, you be careful out there. Don't shoot your eye out!
拉尔菲，你在外面当心点，别把你的眼珠射出来了!
She hadn't seen! She didn't know!
她没看见! 她不知道!
My eye's all right. The BB must've hit my glasses.
我的眼珠还在，弹丸肯定打中了我的眼镜
My glasses! Oh, no!
我的眼镜! 哦，不!
Where are my glasses?
我的眼镜在哪儿？
Few things brought such swift and terrible retribution...
几乎没什么比弄坏一副眼镜
on a kid as a pair of busted glasses!
会令一个孩子遭致更迅捷更可怕的惩罚了!
Stop!
住手!
Oh, no!
哦，不!
Oh, no! Pulverized.
哦，不! 破镜难圆了
For a moment I thought, I'll fake it. They'll never know the lens is gone!
有几分钟我想到了瞒天过海， 他们永远不会知道我只戴了副镜框!
Randomly, my mind evolved a spectacular plot.
但说来也巧，我竟然想出了一个绝妙托辞
Let's see, an icicle!
让我想想，一根冰柱!
Falls off the garage and hits me in the eye!
从车库顶上掉下来差点刺到了我的眼睛!
It would work. It had to work. Quickly, I whipped up some tears.
这应该能行，这必须成功，很快，我就挤出了几滴眼泪
What's the matter, honey? What happened?
出什么事了，亲爱的？怎么了？
What happened? Let me see that.
怎么了？让我瞧瞧
There was this icicle and it fell off the garage and it hit me.
从车库上掉下来一根冰柱打到了我
What is it?
出什么事了？
No, it's okay. Just read your funnies.
没什么，看你的漫画去吧
Wake up, Randy.
好醒醒了，兰迪
Oh, God.
哦，上帝
It hit my cheek and it broke my glasses.
它打到我的脸上把我的眼镜打破了
And I tried to get out of the way, but I...
我是想躲开的，可是我…
There, see, it's just a little bump.
来，瞧，就碰破了一点皮
You're lucky it didn't cut your eye.
没刺到你眼睛里去已经很走运了
Those icicles have been known to kill people.
那些冰柱能要了人命的
What's going on up there?
到底出什么事了？
Nothing. We'll be right down.
没事，我们马上就下来
You stay away from that turkey! It's got an hour to cook.
你别去碰火鸡! 要烤一个小时的
You'll get worms!
没烤熟吃了会长虫的!
But what about my glasses?
那我的眼镜怎么办？
You can wear the old ones with the crack in them...
你可以先戴老的有裂缝的那副
until we get you some new ones.
等以后我们给你配副新的
I had pulled it off!
我蒙过去了!
But I left my gun outside.
可我把枪丢外面了
When you get dressed you can go out and get your gun.
等穿好衣服就可以出去拿你的枪了
Hold that on there.
拿好敷在那儿
Life is like that.
生活就是这样的
Sometimes at the height of our reveries, when our joy is at its zenith...
有时候当我们美梦正酣，正处于快乐的巅峰
when all is most right with the world...
当一切都天从人愿
the most unthinkable disasters descend upon us.
最意想不到的灾难却从天而降
Oh, turkey!
哦，火鸡!
Sons a bitches! Bumpuses!
狗娘养的! 邦普士!
The heavenly aroma still hung heavy in the house. But it was gone.
美如天籁的香味还在空气中飘荡，但火鸡已经没了
All gone. No turkey. No turkey sandwiches.
全没了，火鸡没了，火鸡三明治没了
No turkey salad. No turkey gravy, turkey hash, turkey a la king...
火鸡沙拉没了，火鸡肉汁没了，火鸡杂烩，奶油烩火鸡
or gallons of turkey soup.
还有一大锅火鸡汤
Gone.
没了
All gone.
全都没了
All right.
好吧
Everybody upstairs.
大家都上楼
Get dressed.
穿好衣服
We are going out to eat.
我们出去吃
No! Not, "ra ra ra ra ra." "La la la la la."
不，不是“ra ra ra ra ra”，“啦啦啦啦啦”
Sing like this:
这么唱
Try again.
再来
Stop!
停!
Sing something else.
唱别的吧
No!
不!
Stop!
停!
Kitchen. Bring food. For customers.
去厨房，拿吃的来，招待客人
Oh, I'm sorry.
哦，真不好意思
It's a beautiful duck.
这是只漂亮的鸭子
It really is.
确实是
But you see...
可你瞧…
What?
什么？
It's smiling at me.
它正冲我笑呢
Okay?
行了吗？
Beautiful!
漂亮了!
That Christmas would live in our memories...
这个圣诞在我的记忆之中
as the Christmas when we were introduced to Chinese turkey.
将是我们头回见识中国式火鸡的圣诞
All was right with the world.
一切都天从人愿
Oh, honey, come over here. Look at this.
哦，亲爱的，过来，你瞧啊
Is that beautiful!
真是美极了!
Next to me in the blackness lay my oiled blue-steel beauty.
黑暗中静卧在我身边的是我油光锃亮的蓝钢尤物
The greatest Christmas gift I had ever received...
我收到过的最好的圣诞礼物
or would ever receive.
或者说将来也再不会收到比这更好的了
Gradually, I drifted off to sleep, pranging ducks on the wing...
渐渐地，我沉入了梦乡，在那里枪发鸭落
and getting off spectacular hip shots.
开始了快枪牛仔的辉煌生涯